Guide to the Cayuga Lodge papers, 1937-1997.
Cayuga Lodge papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cayuga Lodge papers, 1937-1997.
37-4-824
Cayuga Lodge (Cornell University)
4.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, printed materials, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Include materials documenting the history of this men's cooperative residence (now co-ed, formerly Llenroc Lodge and Cayuga Student Resident Association)
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Include house minutes of this men's cooperative residence (now co-ed, formerly Llenroc Lodge and Cayuga Student Resident Association), as well as minutes of its executive committee, board of directors, and board of trustees, and of the Inter-Cooperative Council; committee aned financial reports; and constitutions, by-laws, codes, rosters, and programs of the organization. Also, correspondence, mainly of lodge advisor Edward A. Ott, concerning election of officers, functions of the lodge, name changes, and other business; other correspondents include Robert B. Gervan, Hugh A. Moran, and Robert E. Treman. Also the files of William Ballagh which include correspondence and publications documenting the history of the group during the 1930s and 1940s. Also digital scans of the Ballagh material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cayuga Lodge (Cornell University); Ballagh, William; Gervan, Robert B.; Gervan, Robert B.; Moran, Hugh A.; Moran, Hugh Anderson, 1881-1977.; Ott, Edward A.; Ott, Edward A.; Treman, Robert E. (Robert Elias), 1888-1953.; Treman, Robert E. (Robert Elias), 1888-1953; Cayuga Student Residence Association. Cornell University,; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University -- Student housing.; Cornell University; Llenroc Lodge (Cornell University)
Subjects:
Student housing; Students
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 1-5 restricted to the permission of the President of Cayuga Lodge. Files of William Ballagh are not restricted.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also the thesis Building history: how the Cornell family's brick carriage house became Cayuga Lodge by Rebecca Baker.
CONTAINER LIST
- Records awaiting further description (Box 1-5)
- William Ballagh Cornell Class of 1937 files
  These files and inventory were compiled March 28, 2017 by Tom Ballagh, ’67, BS, Agr., Resident Member 1963-66, Associate Member 1966-67, from materials provided by his father, Bill Ballagh, ’37, BS, Agr., Resident Member 1934-37, President of Permanent Membership Committee, 1937-44; Dick Kline,’64, BS, Agr., ’65, MBA, Resident Member 1960-64, son of Dick Kline, ’39, BS, Agr., Resident Member 1935-39; and others.
  - Digital scans of Ballagh material
  - Correspondence regarding the transfer of documents to the Cornell University Archives, 3/2017 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Member photographs, circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca Journal article Llenroc Lodge Example of Co-op Enterprise, 3/30/1938 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - “Sing to Llenroc” Song Sheet by Delmar Cooper (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Llenroc Brochure, Students Can Live Economically While At Cornell University, circa 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Westminster Presbyterian Student Society Brochure, 13934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Ott personal letter to Bill Ballagh remarking on house maintenance projects, circa 7/20/1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Llenroc Lodge Association new member welcome letter, 8/8/1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Llenroc Lodge Bulletin No. 2 “Living at Llenroc Lodge, circa Fall 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Llenroc Lodge Association letter of commendation to Bill Ballagh, 3/11/1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Resolution by Board of Directors expressing appreciation to Bill Ballagh for 1936-1937 service (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Llenroc thanking the Association for commendation, 3/28/1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Llenroc Social Committee letter to Bill Ballagh, 4/5/1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Llenroc Lodge Association Permanent Membership invitation to Bill Ballagh, 4/27/1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bill Ballagh acceptance of Permanent Membership status, 5/1/1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Permanent Membership Certificates, Cayuga Student Residence Association and Llenroc Lodge Association for Bill Ballagh, 5/3,26/1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Llenroc Lodge Cost Records as of July 1937, 7/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Analysis of Purchase Price of Llenroc Lodge prepared by Bill Ballagh, circa 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Llenroc Lodge Bulletin #1 prepared by Edward A. Ott, circa Summer 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding house inventory, 8/4/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Allan Treman to Bill Ballagh regarding preparation of certificate of incorporation, 8/5/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding progress on certificate of incorporation, 8/17/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Llenroc Lodge letter from Jim Woodbury to Bill Ballagh requesting for assistance on progress of transfer of property, 10/5/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Allan Treman to Bill Ballagh on proposed Certificate of Incorporation for Llenroc Lodge Association Incorporated, 10/9/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding signing application for incorporation charter, 10/9/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh on incorporation progress and operation of the house, 10/14/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding signing application for incorporation charter, 10/26/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Richard Milk to Bill Ballagh on reservations of signing incorporation charter, 11/9/1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding the review of the Constitution and By-Laws and update on progress of the operation of the Lodge, 11/16/1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Certification of Election of Permanent Membership Committee Officers for 1937-1938, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - By-Laws of Llenroc Lodge Association, copy of Bill Ballagh, circa Fall 1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Revision of Constitution Report by Dr. Ott shared with Ballagh and F. Rosevear, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Proposed Revised Constitution for Llenroc Lodge Association with revision notes by Bill Ballagh, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Llenroc Lodge Code Book, circa Fall 1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh announcing the incorporated association, 12/7/1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Llenroc Lodge Permanent Membership Bulletin No.1 announcing approval for the charter of incorporation by the State of New York, circa 2/1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Llenroc Lodge Permanent Membership Bulletin No. 2, circa Spring 1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Llenroc Lodge Permanent Membership Bulletin No. 3 effective 3/29/1938 at a joint meeting of the Permanent Membership Committee and Resident Membership Committee, 3/31/1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Llenroc Lodge Permanent Membership Bulletin No. 4 announcing Annual Meeting 6/11/1938, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Dick Milk to Bill Ballagh explaining the purpose of the Annual Meeting on 6/11/1938 to officially sign the papers for the transfer of the house to the cooperative association, 3/24/1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Program brochure for Banquet and Joint Meeting, 3/29/1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Summer School Committee to Permanent Members updating progress of Lodge, 4/14/1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Llenroc Lodge Summer School Application, circa 1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Personal letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding upcoming Joint Meeting in June and progress on house maintenance and membership, dated only “Monday”, 5/1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Llenroc Lodge News Letter, Vol. II No. 1, 6/11/1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Richard Milk to Bill Ballagh requesting to be relieved of Secretary duties, 8/21/1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Llenroc Lodge News Letter, Vol II No. 2, circa Fall 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Llenroc Lodge News Letter, Vol II No. 3, circa Winter 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Jim Woodbury to Bill Ballagh on improvements in the house and request for a meeting of the Permanent Membership Committee, 12/9/1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Partial letter to Bill Ballagh listing names of Permanent Members, 2/1/1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Notice of Annual Meeting of Board of Trustees, 6/17/1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Llenroc Lodge News Letter Vol. II No. 4, 5/16/1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Dick Milk to Bill Ballagh on need for a report to the Permanent Members, 5/17/1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Ed Hume asking him to present letter to the Permanent Members, 6/16/1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Permanent Members on the unique structure of Llenroc Lodge, duties of the Permanent Members and importance to the residents while living at the Lodge, 6/17/1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh advising of Llenroc Lodge extension to an empty house on Stewart Ave. with Ed Hume as the advisor. Discussed updates to the Lodge, 8/26/1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Allan Treman to Bill Ballagh on the issuance of a new bond for the mortgage, 9/27/1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Rubin Close to Bill Ballagh discussing the new mortgage, 9/28/1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Rubin Close acknowledging receipt of above letters, 10/3/1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding name change to Cayuga Lodge Association, circa Fall 1939 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. III No. 1 refers to Llenroc Lodge Annex at 614 Stewart Ave., 10/6/1939 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding Delta Phi protesting Llenroc name, 4/23/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to L.N. Simmons requesting legal advice on Llenroc name, 5/2/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Hugh Moran requesting University advice on name change, 5/3/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Dr. Ott discussing name change, 5/3/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Hugh Moran to Bill Ballagh recommending Cayuga Lodge name with justification, 5/7/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Allan Treman to Bill Ballagh providing legal advice on name change, 5/11/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Cover letter from Bill Ballagh to Dr. Ott enclosing form letter to Permanent Members, 5/11/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Form letter from Bill Ballagh to Permanent Members discussing name change based on University and legal advice and requesting input from the members, 5/11/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Hugh Moran referencing quoting his letter to Permanent Members, 5/11/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Postcard from G.E. Dunham to Bill Ballagh commenting on name change, 5/14/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Ralph Mungle to Bill Ballagh commenting on name change, 5/14/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from L.N. Simmons to Bill Ballagh recommending “Cayuga Lodge”, 5/14/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Ed Wagoner to Bill Ballagh commenting on name change, 5/14/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dan Kurshan, LLD to Bill Ballagh presenting legal advice on name change, 5/14/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Bob Foster to Bill Ballagh commenting on name change, 5/15/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. III No. 2, 5/18/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh discussing Resolution for Annual Meeting, 5/22/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Resolution for name change to Cayuga Lodge Association, Inc. for 5/20/1940 Annual Meeting, 5/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Form letter from Bill Ballagh to Permanent Members explaining Resolution on name change, 5/25/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh reporting on voting of Permanent Members on name change, 6/3/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh discussing problems with name change, 6/6/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from William Burns to G.S. Tarbell discussing name change legal problems, 6/3/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh discussing Referendum ballot for Special Meeting on name change, 6/21/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Llenroc Lodge Special Meeting Referendum for 7/5/1940 Special Meeting for approving name change to Cayuga Student Residence Association, Inc., 6/21/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh on change of street address to 630 Stewart Ave. and name change to Cayuga Student Residence Association, Inc., 8/6/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Llenroc Lodge Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. IV No. 1 announcing name change and other Lodge news, 6/25/1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership, Board of Trustees through 1943, Permanent Membership Roster and mailing list of prospective members as of 6/30/1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letter to Student Advisor from Membership Committee encouraging recruitment of new members, on Cayuga Student Residence Assn stationery, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Proposed letter to Bill Ballagh for review to all student residents on need to make payments on past due 1939-40 house bills, lists rental cost for each room. Funds needed for upkeep of building, 8/7/1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding his error on proposed letter to residents, receipt of funds from Delta Phi, new “630 Stewart Avenue” street sign, 8/12/1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh on name and address change, new charter recorded on 7/18/1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Llenroc Lodge Assn. Board of Trustees Ballot list of 8 Nominees to elect 4 for 3-year terms 1940 – 1943 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership Roster December 1940 & January 1941 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh requesting review of proposed letter to repair driveway, 9/4/1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Hugh Moran to Bill Ballagh on refinancing loan to Cayuga Lodge, 11/26/1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. IV No. 3, 2/1/1941 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    includes an open letter from Dr. Ott to Permanent Members on high academic rating of members
  - Personal letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh commenting on problems at the Lodge, draft causing high member turn-over, discipline cases and new initiations, 5/6/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol III (sic.) No. 4, 5/19/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Paul Fox to Bill Ballagh offering assistance for Annual Meeting on 6/14/1941, 6/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Paul Fox responding to Paul’s suggestions, 6/12/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Receipt to Bill Ballagh for $5 for subscriptions to Business Week, 7/16/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh discussing payment problems for repointing brickwork, minutes of the Annual Meeting of 6/14/1941, attached recommending maintenance, 7/23/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol V No. 1, 8/10/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh, Richard Haynes and Ed Wagner regarding maintenance needs of the house, 8/14/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership Roster as of 8/15/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Tentative Statement to Permanent Members on the purpose of Cayuga Student Residence Association, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill and Jane Ballagh congratulating them on the birth (11/16/1941) of Donald William Ballagh, 11/28/1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    (Note: Dr. Ott wrote similar congratulatory letters to former residents)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol V No. 2, 1/1/1942 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Personal letter from Bruce Cormack from “Somewhere in Bataan”, 3/6/1942 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    (Note: Bruce was later to survive the Bataan Death March and return home). Letter copied on the back is from Bruce’s mother to Amy Ballagh (sister of Bill). Original of the letter was sent to Bruce in 1987 (see correspondence from Bruce Cormack to Tom Ballagh, ’67 in Folder 16 section of the index
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding financial/employee problems in the Dining Room, 5/6/1942 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh reporting on the election of officers, 5/29/1942 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Form letter from Dr. Ott to residents of Cayuga Student Residence Assn. on the benefits of the Lodge and the need for continued recruiting of new members, 7/14/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh on results of the election of officers and open positions, 7/15/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh with brief update on house activities and request to discuss objectives for a permanent program to develop a practical plan for members, 9/4/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Report from Special Committee regarding ownership of Dining Association, circa 1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Resolution on Cayuga Dining Association, 2/18/1943 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. listing officers through 1945 with vacancies for 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. V No. IV, 7/16/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh discussing vacancies in officers on Permanent Membership, 10/10/42 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Dr. Ott appointing Hartley Martin as Secretary-Treasurer of Permanent Membership Committee, 10/19/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Hartley Martin appointing him as Secretary Treasurer, 10/19/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh with follow-up on officer vacancies, 10-19-1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh requesting appointment of Roland Brill as Vice President, 11/23/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh with copies to Mr. Moran and Mr. Tompkins discussing loss of residents to the Draft and the possibility that the University may take over the Lodge to house military trainees attending Cornell. Proposed Amendment to the Constitution and changes in officers, 12/14/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Dr. Ott responding to the 12/14/1942 letter, 12/19/1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. list of officers through 1945 and mailing list of Permanent Members (Note the number of Permanent Members listed as in Active {Military} Service), 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Announcement of Special Meeting of the Board of Trustees 2/25/1943 to consider Resolution on Cayuga Dining Assn signed by Dr. Ott, 2/19/1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership Addresses as of 5/12/1943, 5/1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. V No. 4, 9/21/1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. VI No. 1, 5/27/1944 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    The stress of the War is evident in Dr. Ott’s reporting. He expressed his appreciation for the condolences received for the death of his sister, Mrs. Hinshaw on January 2, 1944.
  - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. VI No. 2, 8/25/1944 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Form letter by Dr. Ott entitled “NEVER STOP COOPERATING” encouraging recruitment of residents and benefits of cooperative living over fraternities, circa 1944 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Board of Trustees. Dr. Ott submitted his resignation as Resident Advisor which was accepted with regret and many expressions of appreciation, 6/18/1945 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Circular letter from Dr. Ott on his declining eyesight and installation of the “Talking Book Machine” in his library. He requested letters from friends, circa 6/1945 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - From letter from Hugh Moran to Fellow Members of Cayuga Student Residence Assn. announcing the retirement of Dr. Ott and appointment of officers of the Board of Trustees under the war-time powers of the Association Constitution amendment dated 12/22/1942, letter dated 6/22/1945, 1942, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Form letter from Hugh Moran to “All the Old Crowd at Cayuga Lodge”, 8/30/1945 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Announces Dr. Ott had moved from the Lodge and in with his daughter and two grandchildren on their farm. Mr. Moran was very hopeful for a prosperous future for the Lodge. He attached Lee Whitford’s August 8, 1945 extensive report to the Permanent Members.
  - Packet sent to early members of Llenroc Lodge, 12/1/1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    sent to Lee Whitford and returned later by his widow, Jean Whitford following his death
    - Letter from Tom Ballagh, ’67, BS requesting any information they may have had during the formative years of Llenroc Lodge especially Dr. Ott, copies of documents and pictures, 12/1/1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Listing of names and addresses of known living Permanent Members from the 1930’s (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Tom Ballagh on his memories of Llenroc Lodge, 11/9/1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Resident Candidate Orientation Program on the history of Cayuga Lodge, circa 1963 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Llenroc Brochure, “Students Can Live Economically While At Cornell University”, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Llenroc Lodge Bulletin No. 2 “Living at Llenroc Lodge”, Fall 1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding house inventory, 8/4/1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding progress on certificate of incorporation, 8/17/1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh on incorporation progress and operation of the house, 10/14/1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding the review of the Constitution and By-Laws and update on progress of the operation of the Lodge, 11/16/1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh announcing the incorporated association, 12/7/1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Llenroc Lodge Permanent Membership Bulletin No. 3 effective 3/29/1938 at a joint meeting of the Permanent Membership Committee and Resident Membership Committee, 3/31/1938 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Personal letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding upcoming Joint Meeting in June and progress on house maintenance and membership, dated only “Monday”, circa 5/1938 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Bill Ballagh to Permanent Members on the unique structure of Llenroc Lodge, duties of the Permanent Members and importance to the residents while living at the Lodge, 6/17/1939 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding Delta Phi protesting Llenroc name, 4/23/1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. III No. 2, 5/18/1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh discussing problems with name change, 6/6/1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding his error on proposed letter to residents, receipt of funds from Delta Phi, new “630 Stewart Avenue” street sign, 8/12/1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Cayuga Student Residence Assn. Permanent Membership News Bulletin Vol. IV No. 3, 2/1/1941 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Includes an open letter from Dr. Ott to Permanent Members on high academic rating of resident members